JOYDIP ROY

joydipdns@gmail.com | +91-8820089259 Kharagpur, India

SUMMARY

Research Fellow in the department of Electrical Engineering at Indian Institute Technology, Kharagpur. Working with sensors and its applications using IoT. Previously worked as an energetic Electrical Engineer with more than 2 years of experience in the Engineering / Construction industry. Well versed with the following skills: construction, engineering design, supervision.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur, India- October 2017 to present Junior Research Fellow in the Electrical Engineering Department.

- Involved in the development and improvement of a water quality measuring system using an indigenous probe. Parameters that this system shall measure would include conductivity, salinity, pH, TDS, etc
- Working to make the meter totally automatic. Also working to improve the data acquisition and use it for analytics.
- Final outcome is a cheap, portable and commercial **automatic water quality monitoring meter** for use by farmers, and fisheries.

SK Samanta & Co Pvt Ltd - Aug 2015 to October 2017

Electrical Engineer (Field and later in design and engineering)

An EPC Company, specialised in CHP,OHP,SILOS, SCR and WORKSHOPS

- Experience in installation of equipment in Electrical Substation- such as HT Switchgear, PMCC, MCC, MLDB, PLC/RIO, Bus duct, Transformer, Battery charger, Ventilation System, Capacitor Bank with ACDB, laying and termination of LT & HT(heat shrinkable) cables, Cable tray arrangements, Illumination(indoor, outdoor and peripheral), Earthing and Lightning protection.
- Experience in conveyor system- Drives, Safety switches and Shuttle conveyor
- Experience in Bunker System- Travelling tripper, Plough/Paddle feeder
- Experience in Track hopper- Wagon Tippler
- Experience in design engineering- AUTOCAD drawings, Cable calculations and schedules, Illumination system, Earthing calculations, approval of drawings, Inspection of equipment at vendor's workshop, Site coordination.

EDUCATION

B-Tech in Electrical Engineering
 Meghnad Saha Institute of Technology, Kolkata, India
 (CGPA: 8.4/10)

July 2011- May 2015

• 12th Board-All India Senior School Certificate Examination(Computer Science)
The Pentecostal Assembly School, Bokaro, India
(Percentage: 83.6%)

• 10th Board-Indian Certificate of Secondary Education
De Nobili School, FRI, Dhanbad, India
(Percentage: 89.57%)

SKILLS

- Arduino
- MATLAB
- Proteus
- Analog circuits
- Electronics and PCB's
- Engineering installations
- Engineering design
- Autocad
- Project Estimation

AWARDS/ACHIEVEMENTS

- Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering -2015, All India Rank- 1650(GATE SCORE-612/1000, Percentile-98.6%) in Electrical Engineering
- Received **Principal's Award** for being an active member and vice president of science club(physics dept.) in school.
- Organized and participated in Annual Exhibitions at school (awarded the BEST MODEL prize in science exhibition).
- Active participant in quizzes(Won prizes for Science, G.K, Environmental Quizzes and IQ Test)

SUBJECTS OF INTEREST

- Control System
- Digital Electronics
- Embedded_Systems

HOBBIES

- Listening to good music
- Reading about topics of my interests
- Discussing philosophical thoughts
- Engaging in sports
- IoT projects

COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

- C/C++
- JAVA
- MATLAB

LANGUAGES KNOWN

English, Hindi and Bengali